{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Physical Science",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "Parts of Atoms",
    "LastModified": "15 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the basic unit of all matter and chemical element?",
      "answer": "Atoms",
      "choices": [
        "Nucleus",
        "Atoms",
        "Protons",
        "Electrons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the centre of the atom?",
      "answer": "Nucleus",
      "choices": [
        "Shells",
        "Nucleus",
        "Orbits",
        "Protons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is all of the mass of the atom contained?",
      "answer": "Nucleus",
      "choices": [
        "Orbits",
        "Shells",
        "Nucleus",
        "Electrons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the positively charged particles which are present in the nucleus of the atom?",
      "answer": "Protons",
      "choices": [
        "Electrons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Protons",
        "Nucleus"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Subatomic Particles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the neutral particles which are present in the nucleus of an atom?",
      "answer": "Neutrons",
      "choices": [
        "Electrons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Protons",
        "Nucleus"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Subatomic Particles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the negatively charged particles which are present in the outer orbits surrounding the nucleus of an atom?",
      "answer": "Electrons",
      "choices": [
        "Electrons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Protons",
        "Shells"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Subatomic Particles"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered the positively charge subatomic as a component of annode rays in 1886?",
      "answer": "Eugene Goldstein",
      "choices": [
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "James Chadwick",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who coined the term proton for positively charged particle in an atom (1917-1920)?",
      "answer": "Ernest Rutherford",
      "choices": [
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford",
        "James Chadwick"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered the neutral particles, which he called neutrons, in the nucleus of an atom in 1932?",
      "answer": "James Chadwick",
      "choices": [
        "James Chadwick",
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered that an atom is also composed of negatively charged particles which was named electrons in 1897?",
      "answer": "J.J. Thomson",
      "choices": [
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "James Chadwick",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are atoms of the same element with different numbers of neutrons?",
      "answer": "Isotopes",
      "choices": [
        "Protons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Isotopes",
        "Electrons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Theory"
    }
  ]
}